Hello English learners. Welcome back to
another great lesson at English Pod. My
name is Marco
>> and my name is Erica.
>> And today we're going to be building
something.
>> That's right. Uh we've got a lesson
about um construction.
>> Cool. So we're going to be working at a
construction site today and we're going
to learn a lot of cool vocabulary with
different types of tools
>> and we'll also learn some phrases that
you can use to talk about work. So even
if you're not really interested in
building and making stuff out with your
hands, um you will learn some language
to talk about work in general.
>> All right. So before we get started with
this construction dialogue, let's take a
look at vocabulary preview.
>> Vocabulary preview.
>> Well, Marco, we're going to look at two
words now. And like you said, we're
building something in this lesson,
right?
>> Right. We're going to be building a
deck.
>> A deck.
>> All right. So a deck. What is that?
>> Basically, it's an elevated [music]
wooden platform that houses will have
like in their backyards maybe.
>> So, it's a a platform that's a little
bit higher off the ground
>> behind your house.
>> Mhm. So, it's very popular for houses to
have decks and people will put out a
table and chairs and maybe have lunch
out there or something
>> or barbecue or something. Exactly. Y.
Okay. So, a deck. Now they're building
this deck and they they need to follow
some plans.
>> Plans.
>> The plans that we're talking about are
construction plans.
>> Yeah. It's kind of like the map for the
deck, how you're going to build it.
>> Exactly. So we can have floor plans for
example.
>> M. So that that shows you how the the
building looks like where the different
rooms are
>> like a house, right? So it's basically
the map for a construction.
>> Okay, great. So two interesting words.
So, we're going to hear both of these in
the dialogue. Now, why don't we get
started and and find out what's going to
happen as they're building this [music]
deck.
All right, ladies and gentlemen, we've
been hired to build a deck on this here
house and turn this boring and drab lawn
into a backyard oasis. There is one
catch, though. We've only got one day to
finish this. So, I'm going to need
everyone to give 110% today. It's going
to be tough, but we've got a great team
here, and I know that together we can
tackle this project. That being said,
let's get to work. That's right. Now,
remember, we've been over the plans, but
we really need to make sure that
everything is up to code. The home
inspectors here are pretty thorough, so
please make sure you follow the plans
exactly. And remember the carpenters's
rule of thumb. Measure twice, cut once.
Okay, guys. Let's get at it. Bob, pass
me that hammer.
The nails won't go in. The wood is too
hard. I think I'm going to need the nail
gun.
That did it.
>> Hey, do me a favor and help me cut this
2x4. Will you pass me that circle saw
and grab hold of the end of the board.
Now, help me drill some holes in it so
we can place the bolts.
>> I think you should sand the edges. Look
at all these splinters. Someone could
get hurt. Jeez, you got to take pride in
your work.
>> Yeah, you're right. Pass me the sander
and I'll take care of it.
>> Julia, get over here with that level,
measuring tape, and that box of screws.
>> Oh, no. Look out below.
All right. So, there are a lot [music]
of people building the deck. They have
to build it fast. They've only got one
day. So, it's a really big challenge,
huh?
>> Yeah. And I think this is a good lesson
in uh maybe not rushing through
important [music]
projects. Right.
>> Exactly. So, we saw some really
interesting tools that they were using.
So, why don't we look at that first in
language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
>> All right, so we've got some language
all about tools. So, why don't we just
get started? So, they mentioned a nail
gun.
>> Nail gun.
>> A nail gun.
>> So, we all know about hammers and nails,
right?
>> Right. So, the So, the nails are what
you put in the wood.
>> Exactly. Now, this is an advanced tool,
so you don't have to use a hammer. It's
kind of hard to explain, so why don't we
listen to the sound this tool makes?
Well, I guess like its name suggests,
it's a gun for putting nails in wood.
>> Yeah, it it actually uses compressed air
to push nails really fast into the wood.
>> All right. All right. So, they're
nailing some some some pieces of wood
together, but they also needed to cut
the wood. And they said, "Um, help me
cut the 2x4."
>> Yeah, she said, "Help me cut this 2x4."
>> So, a 2x4. This is a very popular type
of wood that you use in construction. A
2x4 is basically 2 in x 4 in.
>> So 2 in high and 4 in wide.
>> Mhm. So it's the most popular and common
type of wood that you would use for
construction. A 2x4. You'll hear it all
the time.
>> So they're going to cut the 2x4. And C
said, "Pass me the circular saw."
>> A circular saw.
>> A circular saw. So a saw we understand
is something you use to cut wood.
>> But you have many types of saws. You
have a band saw, you have a circular
saw. And this one makes this sound.
[snorts]
So I guess it's called a circular saw
because the blade or the cutting part is
shaped in a circle.
>> Yeah. A circular saw. So after they cut
the piece of wood, one of the guys said,
"I think you should sand the edges."
>> To sand
>> to sand something.
>> All right. So if you want to sand
usually a piece of wood, you want to use
paper covered in sand to make it very
smooth.
>> Yeah, exactly. And so um they also
mentioned a sander, right?
>> Uh a sander is basically a machine that
has this sandpaper on it and will do the
hard work for you.
>> All right. So to sand something and a
sander.
>> Now our next word is very related to
sanding some because if you don't sand a
piece of wood, it might have splinters.
>> Splinters.
>> Splinter.
>> So like I said, if you cut a piece of
wood, they're little pieces of wood that
stick out and you can get hurt. They can
get under your skin.
>> Yeah. So tiny tiny parts of wood.
>> Mhm. That's called a splinter.
>> Mhm. A splinter. Okay. Okay. So, why
don't we go on to our next tool? They
were talking about a level.
>> A level.
>> The level.
>> All right. So, this is a tool that all
carpenters have. And it's basically a
tool that has a little bit of water in
it. Right.
>> Yeah. And it helps you make sure that
everything is straight and flat.
>> Exactly. So, that's a level every
carpenter has it. And also a measuring
tape.
>> A measuring tape.
>> Measuring tape. Now, I'm sure if this
was a video podcast, we could show show
you what a measuring tape was and you'd
really understand it, but we'll do our
best to describe it for you. [music]
>> So, a measuring tape is like a ruler
that rolls up.
>> Mhm. Yeah. It's a very convenient ruler
because you can it can roll up and you
can measure something that is maybe 6 ft
or 3 m long and you can extend it and
when you're done measuring, you can put
it back and just put it in your pocket.
>> Yeah. Every every carpenter has one,
>> a measuring tape.
>> All right. All right. So, that's our
last tool that we're going to talk
about. So, why don't we move on now to
Fluency Builder where we've got some uh
phrases that you can use to talk about
work.
>> Fluency Builder.
>> So, when the contractor started giving
them instructions, he said, "I need
everyone to give 110% today."
>> to give 110%.
>> So, when you give 110%, you are
basically trying very hard.
>> Yeah. You you give everything you have
to your job,
>> right? So it's not only 100%, it's 110
more than what's needed.
>> So no lunch break.
>> Exactly. So as they were talking about
the instructions, one of the guys said
the carpenter's rule of thumb.
>> A rule of thumb.
>> So this is an interesting phrase. Rule
of thumb. What does that mean exactly?
>> Okay. Well, you know what? I think we
can understand the meaning pretty
clearly if we listen to some examples.
>> Example one.
The rule of thumb in making a sale is
confidence. Without confidence, you
don't make a sale.
>> Example two.
>> The Taylor's rule of thumb is twice the
circumference of the wrist is the
circumference of the neck.
>> Example three.
>> You don't have to take everything I say
about marketing as a rule of thumb.
>> Um, one of the guys noticed a few
problems. You know, the splinters. Um,
and he said, "You've got to take pride
in your work."
>> Okay. So, to take pride in your work.
>> To take pride in your work.
>> Why did he say that to her? What What is
he trying to tell her?
>> Well, because she made some mistakes.
She didn't do such a good job. He's
wanting her to work harder, work better,
[music]
work more carefully.
>> Okay. And so she can be proud of her
work and say, "This is a job well done."
>> So, when you take pride in your work,
you work so well and do such a good job
that you feel really happy about it.
>> All right. Good. So, why don't we listen
to this dialogue again for the last time
and uh then we'll come back and talk
about construction.
All right, ladies and gentlemen, we've
been hired to build a deck on this here
house and turn this boring and drab lawn
into a backyard oasis. There is one
catch, though. We've only got one day to
finish this, so I'm going to need
everyone to give 110% today. It's going
to be tough, but we've got a great team
here, and I know that together we can
tackle this project. That being said,
let's get to work. That's right. Now,
remember, we've been over the plans, but
we really need to make sure that
everything is up to code. The home
inspectors here are pretty thorough, so
please make sure you follow the plans
exactly. And remember the carpenters's
rule of thumb. Measure twice, cut once.
Okay, guys, let's get at it. Bob, pass
me that hammer.
The nails won't go in. The wood is too
hard. I think I'm going to need the nail
gun.
That did it.
>> Hey, do me a favor and help me cut this
2x4. Will you pass me that circle saw
and grab hold of the end of the board.
Now, help me drill some holes in it so
we can place the bolts.
I think you should sand the edges. Look
at all these splinters. Someone could
get hurt. Jeez, you got to take pride in
your work.
>> Yeah, you're right. Pass me the sander
and I'll take care of it.
>> Julia, get over here with that level,
measuring tape, and that box of screws.
>> Oh no. Look out below.
So, an interesting aspect of North
American culture is uh projects like
this, right? Building a deck or maybe
adding a room to your house.
>> Yeah, that's right. And we call this um
DIY,
>> right? DIY, do-it-yourself.
>> Mhm.
>> So, it's a very popular summer project,
right?
>> Right. So, if you live um in a in a
neighborhood in North America, you might
see like, you know, the dad of a family
outside building something and all his
friends come over and they, you know,
drink beer and build this big thing
together,
>> right? So, it could be a treehouse, it
could be a deck, it could even maybe be
adding another room to the house.
>> Yeah. And you know, it's actually it's
so popular that there are tons of TV
shows about how to build stuff for your
house. And there are a lot of really big
stores where you can go and find like
all of this equipment for building stuff
for your house,
>> right? So, basically, there are these
big stores where you can get anything
from paint to wood to tools. Huge amount
of uh material so you can do it
yourself. Mhm. You can DIY.
>> All right. So, that's all the time we
have for today, but let us know what you
think and tell us if you are into doing
handywork like this, like maybe building
a treehouse or building a deck.
>> That's right. You can come to our
website at englishpod.com and tell us
about it as well. You can also leave
your questions there.
>> All right. So, we'll see you guys there
and until next time.
>> Thanks for listening and goodbye.
>> Bye.
Hello and welcome to our slow English
practice.
>> Hello everyone. Today we have a useful
topic.
>> Yes, today we are talking about tools.
>> Tools. That is a very good topic.
>> We use tools at home.
>> We use tools at work.
>> We use tools in the kitchen. We use
tools in the garden.
>> And we use tools to fix things.
>> Yes, tools help us do many jobs.
>> Let's say that slowly.
>> Tools help us do many jobs.
>> Very good. A tool is something we use to
do work.
>> For example, a hammer is a tool.
>> A screwdriver is a tool.
>> A knife is a tool. A spoon is a tool
too.
>> Yes, because it helps us eat.
>> Today we will learn simple words and
sentences about tools.
>> And we will practice speaking slowly and
clearly.
>> Let's start with common tools at home.
>> Good idea. What tool do you use to cut
paper?
>> I use scissors.
>> Scissors. That is a useful tool.
>> Repeat after me. I use scissors.
>> I use scissors. I use scissors to cut
paper.
>> I use scissors to cut paper.
>> Great. What tool do you use to open a
bottle?
>> I use a bottle opener.
>> Yes. A bottle opener helps us open a
bottle.
>> Repeat after me.
>> I need a bottle opener.
>> Can you pass me the bottle opener? Can
you pass me the bottle opener?
>> Very nice.
>> Now, let's talk about fixing things.
>> Fixing things can be difficult.
>> Yes, but the right tool helps a lot.
>> What tool do we use to hit a nail?
>> We use a hammer.
>> A hammer is strong.
>> A hammer can help put a nail in the
wall.
>> Repeat after me.
>> This is a hammer.
>> I need a hammer. I need a hammer.
>> Please give me the hammer.
>> Good job.
>> What tool do we use for screws?
>> We use a screwdriver.
>> A screwdriver helps us turn screws.
>> There are different screwdrivers.
>> Some are big,
>> some are small,
>> some are short,
>> some are long. Repeat after me. I need a
screwdriver. I need a screwdriver.
>> This screw is loose.
>> I can fix it.
>> Very good.
>> Let's make a simple conversation.
>> Okay. I will ask for a tool
>> and I will give the tool.
>> Can you pass me the hammer, please?
>> Sure. Here you are.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Can you pass me the
screwdriver, please?
>> Sure. Here you are.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> No problem.
>> This is very useful English.
>> Yes. We say, "Can you pass me?"
>> Let's practice. Repeat after me. Can you
pass me the hammer?
>> Can you pass me the hammer?
>> Can you pass me the scissors?
>> Can you pass me the tape? Can you pass
me the tape?
>> Can you pass me the glue?
>> Excellent. Tape and glue are also
useful. Yes, tape can hold paper
together.
>> Glue can stick things together.
>> For example, I can use tape on a box.
>> I can use glue on paper.
>> Repeat after me.
>> I need tape.
>> I need tape. I need glue.
>> I need glue.
>> The box is open.
>> I will use tape.
>> Nice practice.
>> Now, let's talk about kitchen tools.
>> Kitchen tools are very common.
>> We use them every day.
>> A knife is a kitchen tool.
>> A spoon is a kitchen tool.
>> A fork is a kitchen tool. A pan is a
kitchen tool.
>> A pot is a kitchen tool.
>> A cutting board is a kitchen tool, too.
>> Yes, we cut food on a cutting board.
>> Repeat after me.
>> I need a knife.
>> I need a spoon.
>> I need a pan.
>> I need a cutting board. I need a cutting
board.
>> Very good. We must be careful with some
tools.
>> Yes, a knife is sharp.
>> A saw is sharp.
>> Scissors can be sharp, too. So, we say,
"Be careful."
>> Repeat after me.
>> Be careful.
>> The knife is sharp.
>> The scissors are sharp.
>> The scissors are sharp. Use it slowly.
>> Use it slowly.
>> Good. Safety is important.
>> Yes, we should use tools safely.
>> We should put tools in the right place.
>> We should not leave tools on the floor.
>> That can be dangerous.
>> Someone can step on a tool
>> or someone can fall.
>> So, after using a tool, put it away.
>> Repeat after me.
>> Put the tool away. Put the tool away.
>> Keep the tools safe.
>> Do not leave tools on the floor.
>> Excellent. Now, let's talk about garden
tools.
>> I like garden tools.
>> Me, too. A shovel is a garden tool. A
rake is a garden tool.
>> A hose is a garden tool.
>> Gloves are useful in the garden.
Gloves protect our hands.
>> A shovel helps us dig.
>> A rake helps us clean leaves.
>> A hose helps us water plants.
>> Repeat after me. I need a shovel.
>> I need a shovel.
>> I need a rake.
>> I need a hose.
>> I need gloves.
Great speaking. Let's make another
simple conversation.
>> Okay, this time we are in the garden.
>> Can you help me in the garden?
>> Sure. What do you need?
>> I need the shovel, please.
>> Here you are.
>> Thank you. I want to plant flowers.
>> Nice. Do you need gloves?
>> Yes, please. I need gloves. Here are the
gloves.
>> Thanks. Now, I need the hose.
Okay, here is the hose.
>> Great. I can water the flowers now.
>> That sounds nice.
>> This conversation is easy and useful.
>> Yes, learners can use these sentences in
real life.
>> Now, let's talk about asking where a
tool is.
>> That is important.
>> Sometimes we cannot find a tool. We can
ask where is the hammer
>> or where are the scissors.
>> We use where is for one thing
>> and where are for more than one thing.
>> Repeat after me. Where is the hammer?
>> Where is the hammer?
>> Where is the screwdriver?
Where are the scissors?
>> Where are the scissors?
>> Where are the gloves?
>> Very good. Now, let's answer those
questions.
Where is the hammer?
>> It is on the table.
>> Where is the screwdriver?
>> It is in the box.
Where are the scissors?
>> They are in the drawer.
>> Where are the gloves?
>> They are near the door. Repeat after me.
It is on the table. It is on the table.
It is in the box. It is in the box.
>> They are in the drawer.
>> They are in the drawer. They are near
the door.
>> They are near the door.
>> Excellent.
>> Let's learn a useful question.
>> What is that tool for?
>> Good question.
>> If you do not know a tool, you can ask
this.
>> What is that tool for?
>> It means how do we use it?
>> Repeat after me.
>> What is that tool for?
>> How do I use it? How do I use it?
>> Can you show me?
>> Nice.
>> Let's practice with answers.
>> What is that tool for?
>> It is for cutting paper.
>> So, it is scissors.
>> Yes.
>> What is that tool for?
>> It is for opening bottles.
>> So, it is a bottle opener.
>> Right.
>> What is that tool for?
>> It is for turning screws. So, it is a
screwdriver.
>> Yes. Very good.
>> Let's do more practice.
>> Repeat after me.
>> This tool is useful.
>> This tool is small.
>> This tool is heavy.
>> This tool is sharp.
>> This tool is safe.
This tool is safe.
>> Good pronunciation.
>> Now let's talk about buying tools.
>> Sometimes we need to buy a tool.
>> We can go to a store.
>> We can say I need a hammer.
>> Or I am looking for a screwdriver.
>> That is a very useful sentence.
>> Repeat after me.
>> I am looking for a hammer. I am looking
for a hammer.
>> I am looking for a screwdriver.
>> I am looking for tape.
>> I am looking for gloves.
>> Great.
>> Let's make a store conversation.
>> Okay. I am the customer.
>> And I am the store worker.
>> Hello. I am looking for a hammer.
>> Sure. The hammers are over there.
>> Great. How much is it?
>> It is $10.
>> Okay, I will take it.
>> Nice. That was simple and clear.
>> Let's practice important store
sentences.
>> Repeat after me.
>> I am looking for a tool.
>> Do you have a small hammer?
Do you have a small hammer?
>> How much is it?
>> I will take it.
>> I will take it. Excellent work. Now,
let's talk about digital tools.
>> Digital tools like a phone. Yes, a phone
can be a tool.
>> A computer can be a tool.
>> An app can be a tool.
>> A calculator can be a tool. These tools
help us learn, write, and work.
>> My phone helps me set alarms.
>> My computer helps me write emails.
>> My calculator helps me with numbers.
>> Repeat after me. My phone is a useful
tool.
>> My phone is a useful tool.
>> My computer helps me work.
>> This app helps me learn English. This
app helps me learn English.
>> Very nice.
>> Tools can be simple.
>> Tools can be modern.
>> Tools can be small.
>> Tools can be big.
>> But every tool has a job.
>> Yes, a tool helps us do something.
>> Let's review some words.
>> Hammer,
>> screwdriver,
>> scissors.
Tape,
>> glue,
>> knife,
>> spoon,
>> pan,
>> shovel,
>> rake,
>> hose,
>> gloves,
>> phone,
>> computer,
>> app,
>> calculator.
>> Good review.
>> Now, let's practice short sentences.
>> Repeat after me.
I need a tool.
>> I need a tool.
>> I use a hammer.
>> I use scissors.
>> I use a knife in the kitchen.
>> I use gloves in the garden.
>> I use my phone every day. I use my phone
every day.
>> Great job.
>> Let's do one longer practice.
>> Good idea. Repeat after me. I have many
tools at home.
>> I have many tools at home.
>> Some tools are in the kitchen.
>> Some tools are in the garage.
>> I use tools to fix things. I use tools
to fix things.
>> I use tools to cook food.
>> I use tools to clean the garden.
>> I always use tools carefully.
>> Excellent.
>> I like this topic.
>> Me, too. Tools are part of daily life.
>> We can talk about tools at home. We can
talk about tools at work.
>> We can talk about tools in a store.
>> And we can ask for tools politely. Yes.
Can you pass me the hammer, please?
Where are the scissors?
>> I am looking for tape.
>> How do I use this tool?
>> These sentences are simple and useful.
>> Before we finish, let's repeat the most
important phrase.
>> Repeat after me. Can you pass me the
tool, please?
>> Can you pass me the tool, please?
>> Where is the tool?
>> What is this tool for?
>> I can use this tool.
>> I will use it carefully.
>> Wonderful work today.
>> Yes, you practiced many useful words.
>> You practiced questions. You practiced
answers
>> and you practiced real daily English.
>> Keep listening.
>> Keep repeating.
>> Keep speaking slowly and clearly.
>> Thank you for practicing with us today.
>> We hope this lesson helped you.
>> See you in the next English practice.
>> Goodbye and keep practicing.
>> The English Pod audio review.
Listen to the meaning then say the
vocabulary word.
A circular saw mounted under a table or
bench so that large pieces of wood could
be cut.
Table saw
to try your best
to give 110%.
A decorative strip used for
ornamentation or finishing on the edges
of a wall.
Molding
A piece of wood that is 2 in thick and 4
in wide.
2x4.
A wall or ceiling constructed of a
prefabricated material such as plaster
board or paneling.
Drywall.
Let your effort be a reflection of your
skill.
Take pride in your work.
A person or firm that supplies materials
or labor for other companies.
Contractor.
>> Set of actions to complete a task.
Plans.
A person who makes or repairs wooden
structures.
Carpenter.
A tool used to measure how long
something is.
measuring tape.
>> Let's try that faster.
Let your effort be a reflection of your
skill.
Take pride in your work.
A circular saw mounted under a table or
bench so that large pieces of wood could
be cut.
Table saw.
A piece of wood that is 2 in thick and 4
in wide.
2x4
to try your best
to give 110%.
A decorative strip used for
ornamentation or finishing on the edges
of a wall.
Molding.
A tool used to measure how long
something is.
Measuring tape.
>> Set of actions to complete a task.
plans.
A person or firm that supplies materials
or labor for other companies.
Contractor,
>> a wall or ceiling constructed of a
prefabricated material such as plaster
board or paneling.
Drywall,
a person who makes or repairs wooden
structures.
Carpenter.
Now say the word and hear it in a
sentence
to give 110%.
It's not enough to try your best. You
have to give 110% if you want to be
successful.
To give 110%
We really have to give 110% today if we
want to finish this project on time.
To give 110%.
Good job team. You really gave 110% out
there today.
2x4.
We need another 2x4 to finish this deck.
I can't come to work today because a 2x4
fell from my roof and hit me on the
head.
2x4.
Did you see that? That wrestler pulled
out a 2x4 and broke it on the other
guy's back.
Take pride in your work.
When you take pride in your work, you
will start to enjoy it more and may even
want to learn more to improve yourself.
Take pride in your work.
I respect Jim a lot because he really
takes pride in his work and is very
dedicated.
Take pride in your work.
How can I take pride in my work if I
don't enjoy what I'm doing?
Plans.
Carl, I need the kitchen plans today so
I can start putting up the kitchen
cabinets.
Plans.
These floor plans are in Chinese. We
need to get them translated before we
start construction
plans.
Our
architect isn't done drawing our floor
plans, but I'm sure the house is going
to look great.
Measuring tape.
This measuring tape is in inches. I need
one that has centimeters on it.
Measuring tape.
Measuring tapes were originally used by
tailor and dress makers.
Measuring tape.
Check out my new digital measuring tape.
All I have to do is point at an object
and it will tell me how far away it is.
[music]
The English Pod audio review.
Listen to the meaning, then say the
vocabulary word.
A circular saw mounted under a table or
bench so that large pieces of wood could
be cut.
Table saw
to try your best
to give 110%.
A decorative strip used for
ornamentation or finishing on the edges
of a wall.
Molding.
A piece of wood that is 2 in thick and 4
in wide.
2x4
a wall or ceiling constructed of a
prefabricated material such as plaster
board or paneling.
Drywall.
Let your effort be a reflection of your
skill.
Take pride in your work.
A person or firm that supplies materials
or labor for other companies.
Contractor.
Set of actions to complete a task.
Plans.
A person who makes or repairs wooden
structures.
Carpenter.
A tool used to measure how long
something is.
measuring tape.
>> Let's try that faster.
Let your effort be a reflection of your
skill.
Take pride in your work.
A circular saw mounted under a table or
bench so that large pieces of wood could
be cut.
Table saw.
A piece of wood that is 2 in thick and 4
in wide.
2x4
to try your best
to give 110%.
A decorative strip used for
ornamentation or finishing on the edges
of a wall.
Molding,
a tool used to measure how long
something is.
Measuring tape,
>> set of actions to complete a task.
plans.
A person or firm that supplies materials
or labor for other companies.
Contractor,
a wall or ceiling constructed of a
prefabricated material such as plaster
board or paneling.
Drywall,
a person who makes or repairs wooden
structures.
Carpenter.
Now say the word and hear it in a
sentence.
To give 110%.
It's not enough to try your best. You
have to give 110% if you want to be
successful.
To give 110%
We really have to give 110% today if we
want to finish this project on time.
To give 110%.
Good job team. You really gave 110% out
there today.
2x4.
We need another 2x4 to finish this deck.
I can't come to work today because a 2x4
fell from my roof and hit me on the
head.
2x4.
Did you see that? That wrestler pulled
out a 2x4 and broke it on the other
guy's back.
Take pride in your work.
When you take pride in your work, you
will start to enjoy it more and may even
want to learn more to improve yourself.
Take pride in your work.
I respect Jim a lot because he really
takes pride in his work and is very
dedicated.
Take pride in your work.
How can I take pride in my work if I
don't enjoy what I'm doing?
Plans.
Carl, I need the kitchen plans today so
I can start putting up the kitchen
cabinets.
Plans.
These floor plans are in Chinese. We
need to get them translated before we
start construction
plans.
Our architect isn't done drawing our
floor plans, but I'm sure the house is
going to look great.
Measuring tape.
This measuring tape is in inches. I need
one that has centimeters on it.
Measuring tape.
Measuring tapes were originally used by
tailor and dress makers.
Measuring tape.
Check out my new digital measuring tape.
All I have to do is point at an object
and it will tell me how far away it is.