Hello English [music] learners and
welcome back to English Pod. My name is
Marco.
>> And I'm Erica. And today we have an
elementary lesson for you and we are at
the supermarket. That's right. We're at
the grocery store and we're going to
learn some language you can use when you
want to pay for your groceries. So this
lesson was requested by one of our users
that wanted vocabulary and different
phrases that are used
in the supermarket when the person is
about to pay for all the things they
need. That's right. And we also have
some great language that the person who
is actually
selling the the groceries can use. All
right. So let's listen to our dialogue
for the first time and see what [music]
happens.
Excuse me, sir. This is the express
checkout lane for people who have 15
items or fewer.
It looks like you have more than 15
items there. Oh, come on. I have 16
items. Cut me some slack, will you?
Fine. Please place your items on the
belt and push your shopping cart
through.
Do you prefer paper or plastic? Plastic.
I also have a couple of coupons. Uh no
problem. I'll take those.
Sir, these coupons expired yesterday.
Darn.
Oh, well. I guess it's just not my day.
Thanks anyway. Do you have a club card
or will it be cash? Yeah, I got a club
card. Here you go.
Will this be debit or credit? Debit,
please. Also, could I get cash back? $50
would be great.
Yeah,
Your total is $78.33.
Here's your receipt. Have a nice day.
Thank you.
Well, [music] we can see in this
dialogue that the guy was able to buy
his food and and you know, they were
using some really interesting helpful
language. That's right. And so why don't
we look at this language now in language
takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay, we have six words for you today.
And the first one, the girl, the
cashier, says this is the express
checkout lane. All right. So checkout
lane. The checkout lane. So the checkout
lane is the place where you get in line
to pay for all the goods you bought.
Right. So the checkout lane. Now, why
did she say express checkout lane?
>> So in in grocery stores or in
supermarkets, sometimes you have a
specific checkout lane that's faster.
Okay. Because people have less things.
So express is the faster checkout lane.
>> Right, the faster one. All right. So
next she tells the guy to put your items
on the belt. Okay, the belt.
>> The belt. A belt. Now we know belt as
the thing you put around your waist.
>> To keep your pants up.
>> Right. But in a supermarket, the belt is
the moving table that you put your
groceries on so the cashier starts to
pass them through. Okay. So the belt.
>> [music]
>> Okay, the belt.
>> groceries on the belt. And then the guy
said that he had a couple of coupons.
Coupons. Coupons.
>> A coupon. Okay. So what what is a
coupon? A coupon is a piece of paper you
can use to get a discount. All right. So
it has a discount on it. A discount for
one thing. Like so maybe you buy some
some apples and you get 10% off one kind
of apple.
>> Very good. Coupons.
>> Mhm. Now he presented these coupons and
she said they were expired. The coupons
expired yesterday. Expired.
>> To expire. All right. So to expire that
means um to be older than the date when
you can use them. Right. So why don't we
listen to some other examples of how we
can use expired so we can understand a
little bit better.
Example one.
I'm sorry, sir. This credit card expired
5 years ago. You can't use it anymore.
Example two.
My driver's license expires in a month,
so I have to get it renewed.
Example three.
Don't drink that. The milk has expired.
Okay. So we can see his coupons expired.
So they were too old and he couldn't use
them anymore. Exactly.
And now finally she asked him if he
wants to pay with his club card or cash.
So club card. Club card.
>> What's a club card? So in some
supermarkets you can receive a special
type of credit card that you can only
use for grocery shopping. And only in
that store. Right. So that is a club
card. All right. So a club card. Okay.
So he's going to pay with a card, but he
also asked for some cash back. Cash
back. Could I get cash back? Cash back.
Now what what's he talking about? Can he
get cash back? He's paying with a card.
What does he want to do? Well, what
happens is sometimes suppose your
groceries cost $20. Okay. So instead of
charging $20 to your credit card or your
club card, you say, "Okay, put $70."
So then the cashier can give you $50
back so you can have cash in your
pocket.
>> Ah, so instead of going to the ATM, you
can get your money in one spot.
>> Exactly.
>> All right.
>> cash back. Interesting. Well, why don't
we hear this one more time in the
dialogue, but let's slow it down a
little so we can understand better.
>> [music]
>> Excuse me, sir. This is the express
checkout lane for people that have 15
items or fewer.
It looks like you have more than 15
items there.
OH, COME ON.
I have 16 items. Cut me some slack, will
you? Fine.
Please place your items on the belt and
push your shopping cart through. Do you
prefer paper or plastic? Plastic.
I also have a couple of coupons.
No problem. I'll take those.
Sir, these coupons expired yesterday.
Darn.
Oh, well. I guess it's just not my day.
Thanks anyway.
Do you have a club card or will it be
cash? Yeah, I got a club card. Here you
go. Will this be debit or credit? Debit,
please. Also, could I get cash back? $50
would be great.
Yeah, sure.
Your total is $78.33.
Here is your receipt. Have a nice day.
Thank you.
All right. [music] So now that we've
listened to the dialogue for the second
time, it's time for us to take a look at
some phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay, we have three phrases for you now.
Well, the guy was not having a very good
day, was he? So he couldn't go in the
express checkout lane and he says, "Cut
me some slack." Cut me some slack.
>> To cut someone some slack. All right.
Now this is an interesting and very
informal phrase. So before we explain
it, why don't we listen to a couple of
other examples?
Example one.
Cut me some slack. I'm only 2 minutes
late.
Example two.
My wife just had a baby and I'm so
tired. Cut me some slack. I'll send you
the report tomorrow.
Example three.
Emily had a really bad week. I think you
should cut her some slack.
Okay. I think I can understand it means
relax the rules a little bit. Right. So
don't be so strict on me.
>> Yeah, don't be so hard.
>> Mhm.
>> Now, I know this this phrase actually
comes from mountain climbing. Oh,
really? Oh, because of the rope.
>> Yeah. So it's just it's like saying
the slack is loose rope. So he's just
saying give me a little bit more
freedom.
>> more freedom. Oh, interesting.
>> Yep. To cut somebody some slack. Well,
now the cashier asked him a question.
She says, "Do you prefer paper or
plastic?" Do you prefer paper or
plastic?
>> Paper or plastic? Now this is the common
cliche phrase that any grocery store
cashier will use, right?
>> Yeah. So paper or plastic what?
>> Bags. Paper or plastic bags.
>> All right. So you'll hear this all the
time in every grocery store. Do you want
paper or plastic?
>> Right. So you can choose plastic bags or
paper bags.
>> Okay. Remember this one cuz when you get
it right, you'll sound really native
like. Very good. And our last phrase,
since he wasn't really having a good
day, he said, "It's just not my day."
>> It's just not my day.
>> It's not my day. Okay. So when it's not
your day it means the day has been hard.
You've not really lucky. Yeah, it's not
it's not a good day for you. Not a good
day.
All right, so let's listen to the
dialogue for the last time and then
we'll come back and talk a little bit
about grocery stores [music] in America.
Excuse me, sir. This is the express
checkout lane for people who have 15
items or fewer.
It looks like you have more than 15
items there. Oh, come on. I have 16
items. Cut me some slack, will you?
Fine. Please place your items on the
belt and push your shopping cart
through.
Do you prefer paper or plastic? Plastic.
I also have a couple of coupons. Uh no
problem. I'll take those.
Sir, these
Darn.
Oh, well. I guess it's just not my day.
Thanks anyway. Do you have a club card
or will it be cash? Yeah, I got a club
card. Here you go.
Will this be debit or credit? Debit,
please. Also, could I get cash back? $50
would be great. Yeah, sure.
Your total is $78.33.
Here's your receipt. Have a nice day.
>> [music]
>> Well, one interesting thing I know about
grocery stores in America is that the
people who are the cashiers are very
often students. Right. It's a very
popular summer job or part-time job with
like college students. Yeah, or even um
in my hometown it was the most common
job for high school students. After
school, if you went to the grocery store
between 4:00 and 9:00 at night, every
single cashier would be a high school
student. And the interesting thing is
that the cashiers are usually women,
right?
>> Yeah, always the high school girls who
are the cashiers. And so the high school
boys would be working in the back, uh
maybe in the warehouse, carrying boxes,
or stocking the shelves.
>> So, putting the cans on the shelves,
right?
>> Exactly. It's a very popular part-time
job for students uh in the United
States, but also uh coupons are very
popular in America. Yeah, what is it
what is it about coupons? What Well,
usually, for example, in the Sunday
newspaper, you will receive a lot of
coupons. Okay. Uh you go to the grocery
store and you have all these coupons for
like cookies or a promotion on um on
some type of soda or drink. So, it's
very popular. People go grocery shopping
and then present all these coupons. And
actually, you can end up saving a good
amount of money. I know the coupons are
usually like save 2 cents or save 25
cents, but I guess if you put all of
those together, you can save money. It's
interesting because people actually will
buy that product just because they have
a coupon for it.
Coupons and high school checkout girls.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, guys, um thanks for listening to
this show. Now, remember, if you have
any questions about the language we were
talking about in this show, please visit
our website at englishpod.com.
Right, leave all your questions and
comments there. And also, if you have
any other suggestions or any doubts,
[music] please let us know and well,
we'll see you guys there. So, thanks for
listening and until next time. Bye.
>> [music]
>> Hello and welcome. Hello. I am happy to
practice today. Me, too.
Today, we will talk about the
supermarket cashier. This is a very
useful topic. Yes. We go to the
supermarket often. We buy food, drinks,
fruit, vegetables, and other things.
And after shopping, we go to the
cashier. The cashier scans our items.
The cashier tells us the total price.
And we pay with cash or card.
Today, we will practice simple English
for this situation. We will speak
slowly. We will use easy words. And we
will repeat important phrases.
Great. Let's begin with a simple
greeting. Okay. I will be the customer.
And I will be the cashier. Sounds good.
Hello. How are you today? I'm good.
Thank you. How are you?
I'm good. Thanks.
This is a nice and simple greeting. Yes.
At the cashier, we can be polite. We can
say hello. We can say, "How are you?"
We can say, "I'm good. Thank you." Let's
practice.
Repeat after me.
Hello. Hello.
How are you today?
I'm good. Thank you. I'm good. Thank
you.
I'm good. Thanks. I'm good. Thanks.
Very good.
Now, what does the cashier often ask?
The cashier may ask, "Did you find
everything okay?"
That is very common.
It means, "Did you find all the things
you wanted?" The customer can say, "Yes,
I did." Or "Yes, thank you."
Or "No, I could not find the milk."
Good. Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
"Did you find everything okay?" "Did you
find everything okay?"
"Yes, I did." "Yes, I did." "Yes, thank
you."
"Yes, thank you."
"I could not find the milk." "I could
not find the milk."
"I could not find the bread." "I could
not find the bread."
Great speaking.
Now, let's make a short conversation.
Hello. "Did you find everything okay?"
"Yes, I did. Thank you."
Great. I can help you here. Thank you.
Very simple.
And very useful.
Now, let's talk about items.
Items means the things you buy.
For example, bread is an item.
Milk is an item. Apples are items.
Rice is an item.
At the cashier, you put your items on
the counter.
The counter is the table near the
cashier.
The cashier may say, "Please place your
items here."
That means put your things here.
The customer can say, "Sure."
Or "Okay."
Or "Here you go."
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
"Please place your items here." "Please
place your items here."
"Sure."
"Okay."
"Here you go." "Here you go."
Nice.
Now, the cashier scans the items.
Scan means the cashier checks the price
with a machine.
The machine makes a sound.
Beep. Beep. The cashier scans bread.
The cashier scans milk. The cashier
scans eggs.
And the computer adds the prices.
Then, we see the total.
Total means all the money together.
For example, the total is $10.
Or the total is $20.
The cashier may say, "Your total is
$12."
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
"Your total is $12."
"Your total is $20."
"Your total is $15.50."
Good job. Now, let's talk about bags.
Yes, bags are very important. The
cashier may ask, "Do you need a bag?" Or
"Would you like a bag?" The customer can
say, "Yes, please." Or "No, thank you."
Or "I brought my own bag."
That is a great sentence. Let's
practice.
Repeat after me.
"Do you need a bag?"
"Would you like a bag?"
"Yes, please."
"No, thank you."
"I brought my own bag."
"One bag, please."
"Two bags, please."
"Two bags, please." Very good. Now,
let's make a bag conversation. Okay. "Do
you need a bag?"
"Yes, please. Two bags."
"Sure. Two bags." "Thank you." "You're
welcome."
Easy and clear.
Now, let's talk about paying. We can pay
with cash. Cash means paper money and
coins.
We can also pay by card. Card means
debit card or credit card.
The customer can ask, "Can I pay by
card?"
Or "Can I pay with cash?"
The cashier can say, "Yes, of course."
Or "Sure." Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
"Can I pay by card?"
"Can I pay with cash?"
"I will pay by card." "I will pay by
card."
"I will pay with cash."
"Yes, of course."
"Sure."
Great.
If you pay by card, the cashier may say,
"Please tap your card."
Tap means put your card near the
machine.
The cashier may also say, "Please insert
your card."
Insert means put your card into the
machine.
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
Please tap your card.
Please insert your card.
Payment approved.
It went through.
Nice work.
What if the card does not work?
Good question.
The customer can say, "Let me try
again."
Or I will use another card.
Or I will pay with cash.
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
Let me try again.
I will use another card.
I will pay with cash.
I will pay with cash. No problem. No
problem.
Good. Now, let's talk about receipts. A
receipt is a small paper.
It shows what you bought.
It also shows the price.
The cashier may ask, "Would you like a
receipt?" Or do you need the receipt?
The customer can say, "Yes, please."
Or no, thank you.
Or can I have the receipt, please?
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
Would you like a receipt? Would you like
a receipt? Do you need the receipt? Do
you need the receipt?
Yes, please. Yes, please.
No, thank you.
Can I have the receipt, please? Can I
have the receipt, please?
Excellent. Now, let's practice a full
cashier conversation. Great idea. I will
be the cashier.
And I will be the customer. Hello. How
are you today? I'm good, thank you. How
are you?
I'm good, thanks. Did you find
everything okay?
Yes, I did.
Great.
Please place your items here.
Sure. Here you go.
Do you need a bag? Yes, please. One bag.
Okay. Your total is $18.
Can I pay by card?
Yes, of course.
Please tap your card.
Okay.
Payment approved.
Great.
Would you like a receipt?
Yes, please.
Here is your receipt.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
Thanks, you too.
That was perfect. It was simple and
real.
Now, let's talk about asking about
price.
Sometimes we do not know the price.
We can ask, "How much is this?"
Use this for one thing.
For example, "How much is this bread?"
For many things, we say, "How much are
these?"
For example, "How much are these
apples?"
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
How much is this?
How much is this bread?
How much are these?
How much are these apples?
Very good.
The cashier can say, "It is $3."
Or
"They are $5."
Let's repeat.
It is $3.
They are $5.
Nice.
Sometimes the price looks wrong.
The customer can say,
"I think the price is wrong."
The cashier can say, "Let me check."
This is polite and helpful.
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
I think the price is wrong.
Let me check.
Thank you for checking.
You're welcome.
Good.
Now, let's talk about asking for help.
Maybe you cannot find something in the
supermarket.
You can ask the cashier.
You can say, "Excuse me, where is the
milk?"
Or
where can I find rice? The cashier can
say, "It is in aisle five." Aisle means
the walking area between shelves.
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
Excuse me, where is the milk? Excuse me,
where is the milk? Where can I find
rice?
Where can I find rice?
It is in aisle five.
They are in aisle two.
Thank you for your help. Thank you for
your help. Great speaking.
Now, let's learn polite words. Polite
words are important. Yes, use please.
Use thank you.
Use excuse me. Use sorry. These words
make you sound kind. Let's practice.
Repeat after me. Please.
Please. Thank you. Thank you. Excuse me.
Excuse me. Sorry. Sorry. Can you help
me, please? Can you help me, please?
Thank you so much.
Excellent.
Now, let's do another full conversation.
This time, we will add a small problem.
Okay, I will be the customer.
I will be the cashier.
Hello.
Hello. How are you today?
I'm good, thank you.
Did you find everything okay?
Yes, but I have a question. Sure. What
is your question?
How much is this juice?
Let me check.
It is $4.
Okay, thank you. No problem.
Do you need a bag?
No, thank you. I brought my own bag.
Great.
Your total is $14.
I will pay with cash.
Okay.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Here is your change.
Thank you. Would you like a receipt?
No, thank you.
Have a nice day.
You too. Very good.
We used many useful phrases. Yes.
We asked about price. We talked about
bags.
We paid with cash.
And we ended politely.
Now, let's practice important
supermarket words.
Repeat after me.
Cashier.
Customer.
Bag.
Receipt.
Total.
Cash.
Card.
Price.
Aisle.
Change.
Great. Now, let's use them in simple
sentences. Repeat after me.
The cashier is friendly.
I am a customer.
I need a bag. I need a bag. I want the
receipt.
I want the receipt. What is the total?
What is the total?
I will pay with cash.
I will pay by card.
The milk is in aisle five.
The milk is in aisle five. Here is your
change.
Here is your change. Wonderful.
Now, let's talk about confidence.
Many learners feel nervous at the
cashier. Yes, the cashier may speak
fast.
Other people may wait behind you.
But it is okay.
You can speak slowly.
You can use simple English.
You can say,
"Sorry, can you repeat that?"
Or
can you speak slowly, please?
These phrases are very helpful.
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
Sorry,
can you repeat that?
Sorry, can you repeat that?
Can you speak slowly, please?
I am learning English.
Thank you for helping me.
Very good.
Now, let's do final shadowing practice.
Listen and repeat.
Repeat after me.
Hello.
How are you today?
Did you find everything okay?
Did you find everything okay? Yes, I
did.
Yes, I did. Please place your items
here.
Please place your items here.
Do you need a bag? Do you need a bag?
One bag, please.
Your total is $18.
Can I pay by card?
Please tap your card.
Payment approved. Payment approved.
Would you like a receipt?
Yes, please.
Have a nice day.
Thanks, you too.
Excellent practice.
Today we learned English for the
supermarket cashier.
We learned greetings.
We learned how to ask for a bag.
We learned how to pay.
We learned how to ask about price.
We learned how to ask for help. And we
practiced polite English.
Remember, you do not need perfect
English. You need simple and clear
English.
Speak slowly.
Repeat often.
Practice every day.
And build confidence step by step.
Thank you for listening.
Thank you for practicing with us.
Keep listening. Keep repeating.
Keep speaking.
Have a wonderful day.
See you next time.
The English pod audio review.
Listen to the meaning, then say the
vocabulary word.
The place you line up to pay for the
things you want.
Checkout lane.
To supply a shop with merchandise.
Stock.
Don't be so strict. Bend the rules.
Cut me some slack.
A place where goods are stored prior to
their sale or distribution.
Warehouse.
To no longer be valid after a period of
time.
Expire.
Domestic birds such as chickens,
turkeys, ducks, or geese raised for meat
or eggs.
Poultry.
A person, usually a teenager, that works
at a supermarket and places groceries
that a person buys in plastic or paper
bags.
Bag boy.
Charging more money to your card in
order to receive cash back.
Cash back.
An arrangement of numbers and parallel
lines on a package, which can be
electronically scanned at a checkout to
give the price of the goods.
Barcode.
A lot of bad things happened to me
today.
It is just not my day.
Let's try that faster.
A place where goods are stored prior to
their sale or distribution.
Warehouse.
A lot of bad things happened to me
today.
It is just not my day.
The place you line up to pay for the
things you want.
Checkout lane.
Don't be so strict. Bend the rules.
Cut me some slack.
Charging more money to your card in
order to receive cash back.
Cash back.
An arrangement of numbers and parallel
lines on a package, which can be
electronically scanned at a checkout to
give the price of the goods.
Barcode.
To no longer be valid after a period of
time.
Expire.
Domestic birds such as chickens,
turkeys, ducks, or geese raised for meat
or eggs.
Poultry.
A person, usually a teenager, that works
at a supermarket and places groceries
that a person buys in plastic or paper
bags.
Bag boy.
To supply a shop with merchandise.
Stock.
Now say the word and hear it in a
sentence.
Checkout lane.
Excuse me, can you tell me where the
checkout lane is?
Checkout lane.
There are so many people waiting in line
at the checkout lane.
Checkout lane.
I hate coming to this grocery store
because they don't have enough checkout
lanes.
Cut me some slack.
Cut me some slack. I'm only 2 minutes
late.
Cut me some slack.
My wife just had a baby and I'm so
tired. Cut me some slack. I'll send you
the report tomorrow.
Cut me some slack.
Emily had a really bad week. I think you
should cut her some slack.
Expire.
I'm sorry, sir. This credit card expired
5 years ago. You can't use it anymore.
Expire.
My driver's license expires in a month,
so I have to get it renewed.
Expire.
Don't drink that. The milk has expired.
Cash back.
I wanted to get cash back at the grocery
store, but the cashier said they had a
policy against it.
Cash back.
Can I get cash back if I pay with my
credit card?
Cash back.
Cash back is the most convenient way to
get cash in case of an emergency without
paying additional fees.
It is just not my day.
I spilled coffee in the morning and got
a flat tire on my way home. It's just
not my day today.
It is just not my day.
Today was just not my day. I have too
many things to do in so little time.
It is just not my day.
I need a massage. Today was just not my
day. We had a lot of problems with our
new client.